### **Berker Erol**

Senior Frontend Developer

Address: Prighton, England

Github: github.com/berkererol

Linkedin: in linkedin.com/in/berkererol

Email: <a href="mailto:decoration-color: berkererol@gmail.com">decoration-color: berkererol@gmail.com</a>

Website: & berkererol.com

### **Summary**

Senior Frontend Developer with over five years of experience in building web applications.

- Specialized in frontend development with React and Angular, coding in JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, as well as in C# using .NET framework.
- Experience with UX design principles and design systems.
- Continuous learner who goes above and beyond project scopes to deliver exceptional products.

### **Professional Experience**

## Senior Frontend Developer The BoxOffice Company

August 2023 - present Glasgow, UK (Remote)

Lead frontend developer of the Boost ticketing project, the application behind millions of movie tickets sold each year.

- Spearheaded the development of new features and expanded business capabilities while coding in TypeScript and using React, Redux, and Jest.
- · Added new backend services that handle complex API business logic in C#, using the .NET framework.
- Integrated Sentry plug-in for real-time bug tracking, skillfully identifying and rectifying complex issues, thereby substantially improving product reliability.
- Collaborated with the designers to resolve UX issues in the edge case scenarios, provided corrections, and overall facilitated the design process.

#### TECH STACK

· React · Redux · Redux Saga · TypeScript · Jest · C# · .NET Framework · Sentry · Google Tag Manager · Google Analytics

## User Experience Designer (Design System Owner) <a href="#">Genetec</a></a>

May 2022 - May 2023

Montréal, Canada

Owner UX designer of the Gelato design system, the main reference guide used by UX designers and frontend developers to build new product features.

- Researched, documented and designed new interface components (e.g. Date Input, Alert, Progress) and supervised UX developers to ensure 100% consistency between Figma and component package.
- · Lead the Design Token initiative, which leverages tokens in Figma to accelerate product-specific variations in the UI.
- Inspected new UX prototypes for compliance to the design system, and refined current components in response to new feature requirements.

#### **TECH STACK**

· Figma · Design Systems · Design Tokens · Prototyping · Wireframing · UX Design · UI Design · Stencil JS · Web Components

### Frontend Developer Behaviour Interactive

November 2021 - April 2022

Montréal, Canada

Frontend developer and UX designer assigned for Behaviour Account, a web platform where gamers manage their account.

- Maintained frontend code of the current Behaviour Account website, where gamers can synchronize their progression in the award-winning Dead by Deadlight game on different platforms (Steam, Stadia).
- Led the UX design process (research, design and code implementation) of a major promotion initiative for an upcoming new game, where gamers will redeem a game reward on the web application.
- Refactored the entire frontend application using React for mobile use, established a design system, and implemented internationalization that supports 12 languages.

#### **TECH STACK**

· React · TypeScript · Javascript · Cypress · CSS & SASS · Node JS · Docker · Amazon S3 · OAuth 2.0 · Steam API

## Frontend Developer Intact Insurance

April 2021 - October 2021

Montréal, Canada

Angular developer for building new UI features for Intact's web application for quote generation, used by millions throughout Canada.

- Developed new components using Angular and Storybook while applying reactive patterns in TypeScript (RxJS).
- Built new standalone libraries within the Nx framework for migrating towards micro frontend architecture.
- Implemented comprehensive end-to-end tests with Cypress and increased code coverage from 85% to 100%.
- Independently deployed code to testing environments and prepared Git branches for releases.

#### **TECH STACK**

· Angular · Nx · TypeScript · Javascript · Storybook · Cypress · Jenkins · Sass · CSS · Node JS · Docker · OpenShift · Kubernetes · Micro Frontends

# Full Stack Web Developer OneSpan

January 2020 - April 2021

Montréal, Canada

Developer in the Secure Agreement Automation team, a SaaS application for digital authentication, e-signature and audit trail generation for contracts, used by most credit companies in EU.

- Written bash scripts which cut down new client onboarding time from months to several weeks.
- Developed web accessibility-compliant (ADA) UI components in Angular, with SASS and Material UI.
- Implemented unit tests with Karma and Jasmine, and increased code coverage to 100%.
- Integrated frontend application to Gitlab CI/CD pipelines and performed regular deployments using Docker, Kubernetes and OpenShift.

#### **TECH STACK**

· Angular · React · TypeScript · Javascript · Storybook · Material UI · Jenkins · BASH · Karma · Node JS · Docker · OpenShift · Kubernetes · CSS · JSS · SASS

#### **Education**

Lighthouse Labs Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp August 2019 - November 2019

Montréal, QC

McGill University Bachelor of Science in Architecture September 2011 - June 2015

Montréal, QC

#### **Skills**

TypeScript	JavaScript ES6	Adobe Suite	Figma	Angular v18	Node JS
React v19	Redux	User Research	UI Design	Wireframing	RxJS
HTML	Prototyping	SASS	Design systems	CSS	Jest
Material UI	Storybook	UI Development	French		